A Guide to the Hugh Kenner Papers 1965-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Hugh Kenner Papers 1965-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7826-a, 7826-b
This collection consists of 79 items.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired on 14 and 15 December, 1976.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains typescripts of The Counterfeiters, 1968, and A Homemade World, 1974, drafts, ca. 1965-70, of The Pound era, and drafts, 1972, of A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett. Some correspondence and a few clippings are included.
Contents List
- The Counterfeiters ca. 1968, TMs, 150 p. (Box 1)
  Typescript, final draft with autograph corrections and additions.
- A Homemade World: Chapter 1: So Here It Is At Last ca. 1974, TMs, 16 p. (Box 1)
  First draft, with autograph corrections and additions.
- A Homemade World: Chapter 2: The Promised land ca. 1974, TMs, 27 p. (Box 1)
  First draft, with autograph corrections and additions, AMs, 2 p.
- A Homemade World: Chapter 3: Something to Say ca. 1874, TMs, 29 p. (Box 1)
- A Homemade World: Chapter 4: Disliking It ca. 1974, TMs, 5 p. (Box 1)
  Reprint of Kenner's article The Experience of the Eye: Marianne Moore's Tradition plus typed additions with autograph corrections
- A Homemade World: Chapter 5: Small Ritual Truths ca. 1974, TMs, 33 p. (Box 1)
  First draft, with autograph corrections, additions, and inserts
- A Homemade World: Chapter 6: Classroom Accuracies ca. 1974, TMs, 17 p. (Box 1)
  First draft, with autograph corrections and additions
- A Homemade World: Chapter 7: The Last Novelist ca. 1974, TMs, 19 p. (Box 1)
- A Homemade World ca. 1974, TMs (Box 1)
  First draft fragment, also autograph notes
- The Pound Era: Foreword [ca. 1970], TMs, 12 p. (Box 1)
  3 drafts
- The Pound Era: Ghosts and Benedictions [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 65 p. (Box 1)
  Early drafts, with autograph corrections and additions, includes notes, and letter, Henry Rago to Kenner
- The Pound Era: Space Craft [ca. 1970], TMs, 63 p. (Box 1)
  Early drafts, with autograph corrections and additions
- The Pound Era: Renaissance II [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 56 p. (Box 1)
- The Pound Era: [ The Muse In Tatters] [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 78 p. (Box 1)
- The Pound Era: Motz El Son [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 71 p. (Box 1)
- The Pound Era: The Invention of Language [1970], TMs and AMs, 58 p. (Box 1)
- The Pound Era: Words Set Free [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 24 p. (Box 1)
- The Pound Era: Knot and Vortex [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 61 p. (Box 2)
  Three aarly drafts, with autograph corrections and additions, includes 5 p. notes and 3 p. footnotes
- The Pound Era: Transformations [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 11 p. (Box 2)
  Early drafts, with autograph corrections and additions, includes 2 p. notes
- The Pound Era: Imagism [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 11 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: The Invention of China [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 136 p. (Box 2)
  Early drafts, with autograph corrections and additions plus three sets typed footnotes, 1 p. autograph notes
- The Pound Era: The Persistent East [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 32 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: Vortex Lewis [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 12 p. (Box 2)
  Early drafts, with autograph corrections and additions, includes autograph notes and letter re. Wyndham Lewis drawing
- The Pound Era: The Stone [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 12 p. (Box 2)
  Early drafts, with autograph corrections and additions, includes 2 p. autograph notes
- The Pound Era: Privacies [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 16 p. (Box 2)
  Early drafts, with autograph corrections and additions, includes notes and reprint article on James Joyce
- The Pound Era: Mao, or Presumption [ca. 1969], TMs and AMs, 28 p. (Box 2)
  Early drafts, with autograph corrections and additions, includes 2 p. notes and 1 p. typed bibliographical data
- The Pound Era: Douglas [ca. 1970], TMs, 22 p. (Box 2)
  Early draft, with autograph correction and additions, includes 5 p. of notes of C. H. Douglas, Economic Democracy
- The Pound Era: The Sacred Places [ca. 1970], TMs, 14 p. (Box 2)
  Early draft, with autograph corrections and additions
- The Pound Era: The Cantos - 1 [ca. 1970], TMs, 43 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: O City City... [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 11 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: Syntax in Rutherford [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 39 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: Specifics [ca. 1970], TMs, 7 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: The Cantos - 2 [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 12 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: Inventing Confucius [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 10 p. (Box 2)
  Early draft, with autograph corrections and additions, includes 2 p. autograph notes
- The Pound Era: The Cage [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 81 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: The Jersey Paideuma [ca. 1970], TMs, 11 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: The Last Vortex [ca. 1970], TMs, 12 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: Endings [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 20 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: Footnotes [ca. 1970], TMs and AMs, 42 p. (Box 2)
  Footnotes
- The Pound Era: Unidentified drafts [ca. 1969-1970], TMs, 6 p. (Box 2)
- The Pound Era: Miscellaneous notes [ca. 1968-1970] (Box 2)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett [ca. 1972], TMs, 12 p. (Box 3)
  Introduction plus Table of Contents, First draft, with autograph corrections
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Waiting for Godot [ca. 1972], TMs, 16 p. (Box 2)
  First draft, with autograph corrections
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Murphy [ca. 1972], TMs, 15 p. (Box 3)
  First draft
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Witt [ca. 1972], TMs, 13 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Mercier et Camier [ca. 1972], TMs, 7 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Molloy [ca. 1972], TMs, 24 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett [ca. 1972], TMs, 3 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Endgame [ca. 1972], TMs, 11 p (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Knapp's Last Tape [ca. 1927], TMs, 6 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: How It Is [ca. 1972], TMs, 13 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Happy Days [ca. 1972], TMs, 5 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Play [ca. 1972], TMs, 7 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Radio, Television, and Film [ca. 1972], TMs, 12 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Come and Go [ca. 1972], TMs, 2 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Queer Little Pieces [ca. 1972], TMs, 5 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett [ca. 1972], TMs, 2 p. (Box 3)
  First draft, suggested changes
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett [ca. 1972], TMs, 18 p. (Box 3)
  Later draft
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Waiting for Godot [ca. 1972], TMs, 21 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Early Life and Poems [ca. 1972], TMs, 11 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Early Stories [ca. 1972], TMs, 9 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Murphy [ca. 1972], TMs, 20 p. (Box 3)
  Later draft, with substitutions
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Mercier et Camier [ca. 1972], TMs, 11 p. (Box 3)
  Later draft, with corrections
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Watt [ca. 1972], TMs, 16 p. (Box 3)
  Later draft, with autograph corrections and additions
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Molloy [ca. 1972], TMs, 33 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Stories and Texts for Nothing [ca. 1972], TMs, 6 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Endgame [ca. 1972], TMs, 12 p. (Box 3)
  Later draft, with autograph corrections and additions, etc
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: How It Is [ca. 1972], TMs, 15 p (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Happy Days [ca. 1972], TMs, 7 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Play [ca. 1972], TMs, 8 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Radio, Television, Film [ca. 1972], TMs, 19 p. (Box 3)
  Later draft, with autograph corrections, additions, etc
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Come and Go [ca. 1927], TMs, 2 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Queer Little Pieces [ca. 1972], TMs, 8 p. (Box 3)
  Later draft, with autograph corrections, additions, etc.
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett: Bibliography [ca. 1972], TMs, 3 p. (Box 3)
- A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett [ca. 1972], TMs, 9 p (Box 3)
  Editorial queries and suggestions
- The Pound Era [ca. 1969-1971] (Box 3)
  Hugh Kenner Correspondence re. The Pound Era
- Miscellaneous Correspondence of Hugh Kenner 1969 (Box 3)
- The Pound Era 1966-1972 (Box 3)
  Miscellaneous newspaper and journal articles